<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WordPress on Hi, I'm Alessandro</title><link>https://ceceppa.me/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on Hi, I'm Alessandro</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</managingEditor><webMaster>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</webMaster><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 09:20:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ceceppa.me/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why PHP namespace is better than prefixing</title><link>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/02/why-php-namespace-is-better-than-prefixing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 09:20:02 +0100</pubDate><author>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</author><guid>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/02/why-php-namespace-is-better-than-prefixing/</guid><description>One of the loved WordPress features is: how easy is to install and use 3rd party plugins to enhance our experience. And there are more than 55k plugins we can choose from! Cool, isn’t it?
Is so cool that some users go crazy and start installing too many of them, but this is not what we’re talking about 🙂
The uniqueness problem As a WordPress developer, we want to create a plugin and (maybe) publish it.</description></item><item><title>Composer for modern WordPress development: Why and how</title><link>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/01/composer-for-modern-wordpress-development-why-and-how/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 09:20:02 +0100</pubDate><author>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</author><guid>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/01/composer-for-modern-wordpress-development-why-and-how/</guid><description>As a WordPress developer, I do often rely on Composer libraries to easily manage CPTs, Settings, Infinite scroll, API integration, and much more…
Composer is a tool for dependency management in PHP. It allows you to declare the dependent libraries your project needs and it will install them in your project for you.
getcomposer.org
Beautiful definition, but what does it mean?
We can see Composer like a kind of npm but for the PHP world, and like npm, it allows you to easily install, update and remove 3rd party libraries, or publishing your own private/public ones.</description></item><item><title>Modern WordPress development</title><link>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/01/modern-wordpress-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 09:20:02 +0100</pubDate><author>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</author><guid>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2020/01/modern-wordpress-development/</guid><description>I’ve started using WordPress back in 2008 to develop themes and plugins. And since then a lot has changed in both WordPress and Web development worlds.
For example, I’ve used it as a framework for building about 4/5 web apps powered by VueJS. But also, because of Gutenberg, I had the opportunity to learn and work with React.
What is “Modern” WordPress development? In 2018 at the WordCamp London there was a panel of small companies and developers exchanging their own experience as WordPress development.</description></item><item><title>Demistify Ssh</title><link>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2018/10/demistify-ssh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 09:20:02 +0100</pubDate><author>hello@ceceppa.me (Alessandro Senese)</author><guid>https://ceceppa.me/posts/2018/10/demistify-ssh/</guid><description>My “Demystify SSH” slides for WordCamp Manchester 2018.</description></item></channel></rss>